♪ 信仰  信仰  信仰 ♪
♪ Faith, faith, faith ♪
George Michael - Faith
♪ 宝贝 ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ 我知道你在求我留下 ♪
♪ I know you're asking me to stay ♪
♪ 说拜托  求你不要走 ♪
♪ Say please, please, please don't go away ♪
♪ 我走了会让你心碎 ♪
♪ You say I'm giving you the blues ♪
♪ 或许 ♪
♪ Maybe ♪
♪ 你每一句话都是真心的 ♪
♪ You mean every word you say ♪
♪ 但我忍不住想起往日 ♪
♪ Can't help but think of yesterday ♪
♪ 另一个想让我当 ♪
♪ And another who tied me down ♪
♪ 小情夫的人 ♪
♪ To lover boy rules... ♪
我父亲总是很自豪地说
My father took pride in saying
他把我们家管理得井井有条
that he ran our house like a tight ship.
但这井在我姥姥来看孩子时
The ship got a lot looser when
就没那么多条条框框了
my meemaw came over to babysit.
我赌5分钱
I bet a nickel.
别着急  小饼饼
Hang on there a minute, moon pie.
我教你一点东西
I want to teach you somethin'.
看看你的牌
Look at your cards,
再看看镜子
and then look in the mirror.
我在笑
Hey, I'm smiling.
是啊
Uh-huh.
这笑容告诉我你的牌怎么样
And what does that tell me about your cards?
我喜欢我的牌吗
That I like them?
真聪明  现在呢...
Attaboy. Now...
看着我的脸
look at my face.
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
看到你老
That you're old.
幸好老娘很爱你
It's a good thing I love you.
我再看一次我的牌
I'm gonna look at my cards again.
你不高兴
You're unhappy.
这表示...
Which means...?
你没有好牌
You don't have good cards.
所以呢
So...
我跟你的5分
I'm gonna see your nickel...
-再加25分  -25分吗
- and raise you a quarter. - Quarter?
你可以弃牌啊
You can fold.
不要  我有好牌  你只有烂牌
No. I have good cards; you have bad cards.
我跟
I'm in.
9 5对子
Nines and fives.
可惜了
That's too bad.
3张Q  你输啦
Three queens. You lose!
什么
What?
你不是不高兴吗
But you weren't happy.
-我让你觉得我不高兴而已  -这不是骗人吗
- I made you think I was unhappy. - But that's lying.
你骗了你的小饼饼
You lied to your moon pie.
我诈了我的小饼饼
I bluffed my moon pie.
-其他人也都会这招吗  -谢尔顿
- Do people know about this? - Sheldon,
知人知面
what's on a person's face
不知心啊
is not always what's in their heart.
那样一切都不一样了
Well, this changes everything.
你怎么知道谁能信任呢
How do you know who to trust?
无法知道
You don't.
所以人生才精彩啊
That's what makes life interesting.
姥姥喜欢教我一些
Meemaw liked to teach me things
会让我晚上睡不着的事
that kept me awake at night.
妈  我们回来了
Mom, we're home!
在里面呢
In here!
他不睡觉在干嘛
What's he doing up?
在输啊
Losin'.
什么鬼
Hell is that?
我让小乔治去帮我买啤酒
I sent Georgie on a beer run,
用鞭炮当了报酬
and tipped him with firecrackers.
妈
Oh, Mom.
我难道要让他白干活儿吗
Was I supposed to stiff him?
我吃了好多糖呀
I ate so much candy!
好啦
Okay.
孩子还你
They're all yours.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
有时候人们会问我"杰夫牧师
Sometimes people say to me, "Pastor Jeff,
你怎么知道神是否存在呢"
how do you know there's a God?"
我说"这是很简单的数学题啊
And I say, "It's simple math.
神要么存在  要么不存在"
God either exists or he doesn't."
咱们冷眼来看
So let's be cynical.
最坏的情况  也是五五开
Worst-case scenario, there's a 50-50 chance.
而这几率我很满意
And I like those odds.
这是错的
That's wrong.
谢利  把你的手放下
Shelly, put your hand down.
抱歉  您请继续
Sorry. Please continue.
没事的  玛丽
It's okay, Mary.
你叫谢尔顿对吗
I-It's Sheldon, right?
-是的  先生  -谢尔顿
- Yes, sir. - Well, Sheldon,
那请你来台前说说我哪里错了吧
why don't you come on up here and tell me how I'm wrong.
-别  -好的
- No. - Okay.
大家给他点掌声吧
Let's give him a hand, everybody.
发生什么事了
Mm. What's happening?
谢利会把他给撕成渣渣的
Shelly's gonna eat him alive.
所以...
So...
你说吧
you were saying?
你把概率跟可能性搞混了
You've confused possibilities with probabilities.
根据你的例子  我等会回家
According to your analogy, when I go home
我可能在床上发现一百万  也可能没有
I might find a million dollars on my bed or I might not.
但这算个哪门子的五五开
In what universe is that 50-50?
那你觉得
So what do you think
神存在的几率有多少呢
the odds are that God exists?
我觉得是0
I think they're zero.
我相信科学
I believe in science.
所以你觉得科学跟宗教不能共处共存
So you don't think science and religion can go hand in hand?
科学讲事实  宗教讲信仰
Science is facts, religion is faith.
我喜欢事实
I prefer facts.
我懂
I understand that.
那我告诉你几条有趣的事实
Here's a cool fact for ya.
很多知名科学家都相信神的存在
A lot of famous scientists believed in God.
艾萨克·牛顿
Isaac Newton.
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦
Albert Einstein.
甚至是查尔斯·达尔文
Even Charles Darwin.
所以达尔文信神是对的  而他的进化论是错的吗
So Darwin's right about God and wrong about evolution?
小子上道了
Now you're gettin' it.
大家再给谢尔顿一次掌声
Let's give it up for Sheldon, everybody.
很有风度的好小伙
What a good sport. Oh.
但我并没有风度
But I wasn't a good sport.
在那一刻   我发誓
At that moment, I vowed to come back
我下周日要回来手撕杰夫牧师
the following Sunday and destroy Pastor Jeff.
您好  库珀先生
Uh, hello, Mr. Cooper.
米希在家吗
Is Missy home?
你好啊  比利  她上教堂了
Hello, Billy. No, she's at church.
我给她带了我家母鸡下的蛋
I brought her eggs from my chickens.
我看到了
I see that.
你可以做水煮蛋或炒蛋
You can boil them or scramble them.
好的
Okay.
我喜欢煎蛋
I like fried.
行
Okay.
我不喜欢荷包蛋
I don't like poached.
好吧
Okay.
打扰了
Thank you for your time.
好
Okay.
要我帮你煮了蛋吗  宝贝
You want me to cook those eggs for you, baby?
不要  这些是礼物
No. They're a gift.
抱歉
Sorry.
他还给我写了纸条
He even wrote me a note.
"来自你的神秘仰慕者  比利"
"Eggs from your secret admirer. Billy."
玛丽  你能进来一下吗
Mary, can you come in here?
我在做饭
I'm cookin'.
我真的需要你进来一下
I really need you to come in here.
到底要干嘛
What on earth?
怎么了
What?
你听
Listen to this.
"法国哲学家
"French philosopher,
数学家与物理学家布莱兹·帕斯卡
mathematician and physicist, Blaise Pascal,
表示理性的人应该相信神的存在
argued a rational person should believe God exists
因为如果你对了你就赚到了
because you have everything to gain if you're right,
而如果你错了  你也不亏"
and nothing to lose if you're wrong."
感觉没错啊
Sounds right.
姥姥马上就过来照顾你们  我得走了
Meemaw is coming over to watch you-- I gotta go.
-去哪里  -你们爸爸不舒服
- Where? - Daddy's not feeling good.
我们现在要去医生那边
We're gonna go see a doctor.
-他没事吧  -他会没事的
- Is he okay? - He's gonna be fine.
你们就乖乖坐着
You just sit right there.
姥姥等会就来给你们做晚饭
Meemaw's on her way over to cook you dinner.
我们能跟你们一起去吗
Can we come with you?
不行  乖乖坐着  不许离开
No. Just stay right there, don't move.
乔治  走吧
George, let's go.
我们得坐在这里多久啊
How long are we supposed to sit here?
我不知道
I don't know.
她说不许离开
She said don't move.
说得很清楚了
She was very clear.
希望我不会想上厕所
Hope I don't have to go to the bathroom.
安心吧
Don't worry!
姥姥来了
Meemaw's here!
一切都有姥姥在
Everything's under control!
我们还没吃晚饭
We haven't had dinner yet.
是吗
Really?
可我不想做饭
I don't feel like cookin'.
我丈夫好像心脏病发作
I think my husband's having a heart attack!
需要急救小组与抢救车
I need an RRT and a crash cart.
这边
Over here.
先生  你现在胸口疼吗
Sir, are you having chest pains right now?
是啊  有一点
Yeah, a little bit.
你的手臂有麻木感吗
Any numbness or pain in your arms?
这只手好像有点
Maybe this one.
喘不过气吗
Shortness of breath?
太多问题了吧
Enough questions.
他是个胸口疼的中年胖子
He's a fat, middle-aged man with chest pains.
做点什么啊
Do something!
抱歉说你胖  亲爱的
Sorry about the fat, honey.
你自己说你喜欢我胖嘟嘟
You said you liked me this way.
爸爸会没事的吧
Is Daddy gonna be okay?
没事的  你们姥爷以前
Oh, yeah. Your Pop-Pop used to have
也整天胸口有点疼
little chest pains all the time.
他不是死于心脏病了吗
Didn't he die of a heart attack?
为了保险理赔  是这原因
Well, for insurance purposes, yes.
怎么了
Hey. What's goin' on?
爸爸进医院了
Dad's in the hospital.
什么  为什么爸爸进医院了
What? Why's Dad in the hospital?
-他会没事的  -他胸口疼
- He's gonna be fine. - He had chest pains.
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
那我们还在这里干嘛  为什么不去医院
What are we doin'? Why aren't we going to the hospital?
大家哪里都不许去
Nobody's goin' nowhere.
我们只需要保持冷静
We're just gonna stay calm,
好好吃顿晚饭  等你们妈妈打来
have a nice dinner, and wait for your mama to call
告诉我们情况就行
and tell us what's what.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
你刚才说"为了保险理赔"是什么意思
What did you mean by "insurance purposes"?
乖乖吃你的
Just eat.
哪门子德州人喝桃红葡萄酒啊
What kind of Texan drinks pink wine?
您好
Hello.
妈  孩子们还好吗
Hi, Mom. Kids okay?
他们挺好  乔治怎么样
Yeah, they're fine. How's George?
我也不知道  他们在做一些检测
I don't know. They're running tests.
不用担心我们
Well, don't you worry about us.
一切都在我的管辖之中
Everything's under control here.
好的
Okay.
有更多消息我会再打给你
I'll call you when I know more.
你还好吗
How you holdin' up?
还行吧
I guess I'm okay.
乔治能挺过去的  亲爱的
Well, George is gonna pull through this, honey.
我跟你保证
I guarantee it.
谢谢了  妈
Thanks, Mom.
谢谢你挺身而出
Thanks for bein' there.
那当然
You bet.
我之后再打给你
I'll call you later.
好
Okay.
拜拜
Bye.
她怎么说
What'd she say?
医生在进行一些检测  但我敢肯定
The doctors are doin' some tests, but, dollars to donuts,
你老爸只是严重胀气而已
your daddy's just got a bad case of gas.
你们都该上床睡觉了
Y'all two go get ready for bed.
我不想待在家里
I don't want to stay around here.
我想去医院看爸爸
I want to go to the hospital and see Dad.
我还想去拉斯维加斯看威利·纳尔逊呢
Well, I want to go to Las Vegas and see Willie Nelson,
美国乡村音乐传奇歌手
但那同样不会发生
but that ain't gonna happen either.
这蠢爆了
This is stupid.
你知道什么才叫蠢吗
You know what's stupid?
我得喝桃红葡萄酒
I got to drink pink wine!
姥姥
Meemaw?
干什么
What?
爸爸真的没事吗
Is Dad really okay?
是的
Yes.
希望你不是在诈我们
I hope you're not bluffing.
你睡着了吗
You asleep?
没有
No.
我也没有
Me neither.
每次电话铃一响  我就好害怕
Every time the phone rings, I get scared.
我也是
Me, too.
我要去看爸爸  你们来吗
I'm goin' to see Dad. You guys want to come?
怎么去  姥姥说我们得待在家里
How? Meemaw said we have to stay here.
你到底要不要去
You want to go or not?
嘘
Shh.
那我叫谁嘘
Who do I shush?
-嘘  -嘘
- Shh! - Shh!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要开车去医院
I'm driving to the hospital.
你们可以跟我一起去或留在这里  随你们
You can come with me or stay here-- up to you.
我要去
I'm comin'.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
你才14岁
You're 14.
你根本不会开车
You don't know how to drive.
我在4H营开过拖拉机
I drove a tractor at 4-H camp.
全球青少年组织
就是一回事
It's the same thing.
但你当时是坐在农民腿上开的
But you sat on the farmer's lap.
那你就待在这儿
Then stay here.
走吧  米希
Come on, Missy.
你在干什么
What are you doin'?
路上听听音乐
Travelin' music.
我跟你们一起去
I'm coming with you.
你为什么戴着我的头盔
Why are you wearin' my helmet?
我觉得你开车不会有好结果
I don't expect this to end well.
还带枕头了
And the pillows?
同样原因
Same answer.
关掉  我要专心开车
Turn it off. I've got to concentrate.
好了
Okay,
所有人系上安全带
seat belts, everybody.
拜托你慢慢地开
Please drive slowly.
淡定  我心里有数
Relax. I know what I'm doin'.
常常有人问我
I've often been asked
为什么不愿意学开车
why I never learned to drive a car.
这一晚
This night...
就是你的答案
is your answer.
拜托开慢一点
Please slow down.
我现在时速只有12公里
I'm goin' eight miles an hour.
一头牛刚刚都赶超了我们
A cow just passed us.
-你知道去医院的路吗  -知道
- Do you know how to get to the hospital? - Yeah.
就在冰雪皇后对面
It's right across the street from the Dairy Queen.
哪一家冰雪皇后
Which Dairy Queen?
你在说什么
What are you talkin' about?
有两家
There's two.
真的吗
Really?
你要撞到了
You're gonna hit it!
哪一家是妈妈带我们去吃的
Which is the one Mom takes us to?
你要撞到了
You're gonna hit it!
这下你麻烦可大了
Ooh, you're in trouble now!
喂
Yeah?
你怎么那么久才接电话
What took you so long to answer?
我刚才在补妆  你有意见吗
Powdering my nose. What's it to ya?
抱歉  就是想告诉你最新的情况
Sorry I asked. Just wanted to give you an update.
怎么样了
Y... What's goin' on?
他们还要做更多检测
They want to run some more tests.
今晚他得住在医院
They're gonna hold him overnight.
没什么好担心的
Oh, Oh, well, that's, that's nothin' to worry about.
只是预防措施
That's just precautionary.
孩子们怎么样
How are the kids?
他们有点担心
Oh. They were a little worried,
但我安抚了他们
but I handled it.
他们睡了吗
They sleepin'?
睡了
Yeah, yeah.
当然睡了
You bet.
再次谢谢你帮忙
Thanks again for helpin'.
听好了
Oh, hey,
他们是我的外孙
these are my grandchildren.
是我的血脉
They are my blood.
好吧  我要挂了
Okay. I better go.
行  晚点再聊
Okay. We'll talk later.
外婆亲启
谢尔顿
外婆  我们去医院看爸爸了
乔治开走了你的车
谨上  谢尔顿
要了个亲命
Son of a bitch.
我恨死这些死孩子
I hate those kids.
承认吧  我们迷路了
Just admit it, we're lost.
我们才没有迷路
We're not lost.
反正我没见到哪儿有医院
Well, I sure don't see a hospital anywhere.
我们为什么不找人问问路呢
Why don't we ask somebody for directions?
因为我们是一群开车的小孩  你个天才
Because we're children in a car, genius.
我靠
Dang it!
你是故意瞄准了要撞的吗
Are you aiming for them?
所有人闭嘴  我能行
Everybody just shut up. I got this.
完了  我们要蹲号子了
Oh, no. We're going to jail.
小乔治才要去蹲号子
Georgie's going to jail.
我要说我是被绑架的
I'm saying I was kidnapped.
这主意不错
That's a good plan.
你和我都是被绑架的人质
You and I were kidnapped.
如果我要去蹲号子  你们也跑不了
If I'm going to jail, we're all going to jail.
你赶紧靠边停车吧
Oh, you better pull over.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
-别傻坐着  快跟上那辆车  -为什么
- Well, don't just sit there-- follow it. - Why?
那是救护车  要开去医院的啊
It's an ambulance-- it's going to the hospital.
坐好了
Hang on.
我小小声地放音乐行不
How about I put the radio on real low?
闭嘴
Shut up.
玛丽
Mary.
-妈妈  -他们在哪
- Mom! - Where are they?
你说谁
Where's who?
更重要的是
More importantly...
-乔治怎么样了  -妈妈
- ...how is George? - Mom!
他们在这儿呢
Ah. There they are!
我刚在大厅跟几个小淘气走丢了
Ha! I lost the little rascals in the... hall.
我想见爸爸
I want to see Dad.
-我也是  -我也是
- Me, too. - Me, too.
他现在和医生在一起
The doctors are with him now.
等会我带你们进去
I'll take you in a bit.
他们怎么会来这儿
Why are they here?
这不是明摆着的吗
I think it's obvious.
他们好爱爸爸
They love their daddy.
我知道  但他们怎么没在家睡觉
No, I get that. Why aren't they home in bed?
大家都睡不着
Well, nobody could sleep.
我觉得这样做才对
I thought it was the right thing.
诈得漂亮
Good bluff.
嘘
Shh.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
你们需要什么吗  饿不饿
You all need anything? You hungry?
-不饿  -不用了  谢谢
- No. - No, thank you.
大家在这儿坐着
Okay, everybody sit tight.
我去看看你们爸爸
I'm gonna go check on your dad.
小乔治
Georgie.
把我的车钥匙还给我
Give me my damn keys.
嗯  给你
Oh, yeah. Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我怎么比你们还早到医院
How did I beat you here?
我们一直撞到垃圾桶
We kept hitting garbage cans.
要命了
Oh, God.
我要去洗手
I need to wash my hands.
-这里有些细菌能杀死人  -等等
- There are germs here that can kill you. - Hold up.
你们都喜欢外婆来照顾你们  对吧
Now, y'all like it when your meemaw babysits.
可以玩扑克  吃糖  放鞭炮
Poker, candy, firecrackers.
没错
Yes.
-嗯  -是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
如果你们母亲发现了
Well, if your mother ever finds out
你今晚做的事
what you did tonight,
那以后都没有那种好日子了
that is never gonna happen again.
我不能对我妈妈说谎
I can't lie to my mother.
你当然可以  相信自己
Sure you can. Believe in yourself!
小教堂
虽然看起来是那样
Despite what it looks like,
但我那晚没向上帝祈祷
I didn't pray to God that night.
而是向布莱兹·帕斯卡祈祷
I prayed to Blaise Pascal.
我的想法是
My thinking was,
如果他对关于上帝存在的理论是对的
if he was right about the existence of God,
那他可以帮我转达
then he could pass along my request
让我爸爸好起来的请求
for my dad to get better.
如果他错了
If he was wrong...
这个嘛
well...
在这一刻  我需要他是对的
in this moment, I needed him to be right.
为什么要这么久啊
What's taking so long?
嘘
Shh.
小声点  偷车贼
Keep your voice down, car thief.
我才没有偷你的车  只是借用
I didn't steal your car, I just borrowed it.
总有一天你会需要有人去保释你
You're gonna need to make bail someday.
到时千万别来找我
Do not come to me.
好消息  你们的爸爸不会有事
Good news! Your daddy's gonna be fine.
应该过两天就能回家了
Should be home in a day or two.
是心脏病发作吗
And was it a heart attack?
轻微的  没有造成永久性损伤
Minor. No permanent damage.
真是太好了
Oh! That's wonderful!
我们的祈祷应验了
Our prayers have been answered.
孩子们  快来
Come on, everybody,
我们去和爸爸打招呼
let's say hello to your old dad.
走吧
Come on.
有短暂的一瞬间
For a brief moment,
我内心充满了信仰的治愈能量
I was filled with the healing power of faith.
但第二天  我们全家都病倒了
Then the next day, we all got violently ill
因为吃了比利的鸡蛋  我的信仰也散了
from Billy Sparks' eggs, and I was over it.
今早我想谈谈一切是如何开始的
I thought I'd talk this morning about how it all began.
大家都知道创世的第一天
Now, everybody knows how, on the first day of creation,
神说  "要有光"
God said, "Let there be light."
便有了光
And there was light.
当神见到光  就知道是好事
And when God saw that light, he knew it was good.
又来了
Oh, here we go.
什么事  谢尔顿
Yes, Sheldon.
你说祂第四天才造了太阳
You said he didn't create the sun until day four.
是的
Yeah.
那前三天哪来的光呢
So how could there be light the first three days?
神就是光
God is light.
那么说神是光子
So God's a photon?
是神让光子有存在的可能
God's what made photons possible.
那祂是第几天造出光子的
And what day did he do that?
我想是第一天
I would think day one.
如果我抱胸跪倒假装病发  也许能逃离这里
If I grab my chest and keel over, maybe we can get out of here.
你这话也太不合适了
That's a terrible thing to say.
因为第一天才刚开始
...because the first day had just begun.
那就是在宇宙大爆炸之前吗
So, before the Big Bang?
没有宇宙大爆炸
There was no Big Bang.
只有"道"[一个字]
There was only the Word.
那个字是"砰"吗
Was the word "kaboom"?
好了  快装吧
Okay, do it.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
怎么回事
What's happening?
-结束了吗  -是的
- Is it over? - Y-Yes.